<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Bastien</title>
    <description>I am a developer and aspiring designer interested in tech and startups.</description>
    <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.kevinbastien.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Goals For 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/01/01/My-New-Years-Resolutions/&quot;&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt; from last year I was around 20% successful. Although I didn’t hold myself fully to those resolutions/goals, 2015 was a major year for personal/professional growth. I thought it would be good to reflect on 2015 and find the major things I need to improve on during 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My 2016 List:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut down alcohol consumption by 50%. This means that I should drink less than or equal to 2 times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read 12+ books this year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start a profitable side project, that makes over $5k in revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post 12+ youtube videos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be more optimistic in all aspects of life. Follow the steps to Tim Ferriss’ five minute journal:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 Things I am grateful for&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 things that would make today great&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Daily affirmations. I am…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 amazing things that happened today&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How could I have made today better&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t be stagnant, and always be working on something. Write down the goals you want to accomplish by the end of the day and stick to it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to play the ukulele. Practice at least 2 hours a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn more about music, and how to produce my own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to be curious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;8-10 are not necessarily quantifiable for me right now, but they are still goals that I want to strive for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my list of things that I want to improve on in 2016. Let me know what yours are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/9Cywv3GlwXgly/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;popbottles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 04:31:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2016/01/12/Goals-For-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2016/01/12/Goals-For-2016/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Highlight Series&amp;#58; Swarm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always find myself downloading and trying out new apps. So I thought I would share and highlight the ones that stick out. My goal is to help spotlight some apps that the majority of people are not as familiar with. Hope you find this useful! Enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../images/Swarm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Swarm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I chose the Swarm app. I find myself using this everyday. Swarm, an app from &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/foursquare-find-places-to/id306934924?mt=8&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, is the fastest way to keep and meet up with your friends. With Swarm, you can check in to tell friends what you’re up to, easily see who’s out nearby, and who wants to hang out later. A cool feature they brought back is the mayorship badges. All you have to do is check in more than anyone else and you’ll unlock a mayor crown. Feel free to check out the app and download it &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/US/app/id870161082?mt=8&amp;amp;pt=foursquare.com&amp;amp;ct=swarmcid&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/07/01/The-Highlight-Swarm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/07/01/The-Highlight-Swarm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Highlight Series&amp;#58; Apple Music</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always find myself downloading and trying out new apps. So I thought I would share and highlight the ones that stick out. My goal is to help spotlight some apps that the majority of people are not as familiar with. Hope you find this useful! Enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../images/am.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Music Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is a big day for Apple, once the biggest name in digital music, and now trying to reclaim its title. I think it is only right to highlight Apple Music. Apple went live today with their subscription music streaming service. The cost is $9.99/month for a single user, and what looks promising is the family plan (six users) which will cost $14.99/month. Apple Music is available on iOS, OSX and Windows computers. The service will hit Apple TV and Android soon. Get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/music/membership/&quot;&gt;free three month trial&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/30/The-Highlight-AM/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/30/The-Highlight-AM/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Highlight Series&amp;#58; Postmates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always find myself downloading and trying out new apps. So I thought I would share and highlight the ones that stick out. My goal is to help spotlight some apps that the majority of people are not as familiar with. Hope you find this useful! Enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../images/postmates-img.png&quot; alt=&quot;Postmates Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I thought I would highlight Postmates. Postmates is a logistics company that operates a network of couriers who deliver goods locally. In laymen terms: you can order “almost anything” you want and have them deliver it to you. This app has been getting a lot of attention. Probably due to the fact that it raised $80M during it’s Series C, but also because it is continuing to grow from city to city. Feel free to check out the app and download it &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/postmates/id512393983?mt=8&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/29/The-Highlight-Series/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/29/The-Highlight-Series/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Reads&amp;#58; 6/28</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/TCOnqmevnGbxm/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;hello&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy and constantly find myself reading articles around the web. I then share the “good ones” with my immediate network via social platforms. I’ve been inspired to post my finds each week. Feel free to read the ones that intrigue you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bhorowitz.com/who_do_you_trust&quot;&gt;Who Do You Trust?&lt;/a&gt;: Ben Horowitz starts off with some rap lyrics, then dives into the hair market. Yes, the hair market. The $5B/year market for buying and selling hair.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2015-06-22/beatrayed-by-dre-&quot;&gt;Beatrayed by Dre&lt;/a&gt;: Noel Lee is suing Apple/Beats for stealing the design, manufacturing, and distribution rights to Beats. He built the headphones Apple paid $3 billion for, but didn’t receive a dime. Now he’s suing for his share.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@michalbohanes/seven-lessons-i-learned-from-the-failure-of-my-first-startup-dinnr-c166d1cfb8b8&quot;&gt;Seven lessons I learned from the failure of my first startup, Dinnr&lt;/a&gt;: Michal Bohanes discusses what he learned from the failure of Dinnr, an ad-hoc, same day ingredient delivery service.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2015-06-23/this-is-how-uber-takes-over-a-city&quot;&gt;This Is How Uber Takes Over a City&lt;/a&gt;: This article talks about what Uber did to conquer America’s quirkiest city (Portland), and how the company unleashed its biggest weapon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/theres-only-a-few-ways-to-scale-user-growth-and-heres-the-list/&quot;&gt;There’s only a few ways to scale user growth&lt;/a&gt;: Andrew Chen talks about the major channels that successful products use to drive traction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/28/What-I-Read-This-Week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/28/What-I-Read-This-Week/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Reads&amp;#58; 6/21</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy and constantly find myself reading articles around the web. I then share the “good ones” with my immediate network via social platforms. I’ve been inspired to post my finds each week. Feel free to read the ones that intrigue you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2015-paul-ford-what-is-code/&quot;&gt;What is Code&lt;/a&gt;: This is a great article where Paul Ford discusses what one needs to know about code to survive in a suspicious world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@gerstenzang/16-product-things-i-learned-at-imgur-4e58b936759c&quot;&gt;16 product things I learned at Imgur&lt;/a&gt;: Sam Gerstenzang used to run product at Imgur. He discusses some of the product things that he learned while working there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@shaanvp/10-throwback-startup-homepages-8c15c2b32ed&quot;&gt;10 Throwback Startup Homepages (before they were famous)&lt;/a&gt;: Shaan Purl dug up landing pages from 10 successful startups to determine if they used the 6-word pitch when they were getting off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://get.onemonth.com/29-growth-hacking-quick-wins&quot;&gt;29 Growth Hacking Quick Wins&lt;/a&gt;: Mattan Griffel goes over some strategies you can use to grow your company faster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3046231/the-new-rules-of-work/the-rise-of-the-intrapreneur&quot;&gt;The Rise of the Intrapreneur&lt;/a&gt;: Alyson Krueger talks about how never before has there been such a push for employees to take ownership of their own corner of a company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@BoltVC/how-it-s-made-series-beats-by-dre-154aae384b36&quot;&gt;How It’s Made Series: Beats By Dre&lt;/a&gt;: Avery Louie from Bolt sheds light on how Beats are made and the tricks they use to optimize hardware design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;BONUS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://taylorswift.tumblr.com/post/122071902085/to-apple-love-taylor&quot;&gt;To Apple, Love Taylor&lt;/a&gt;: Taylor Swift writes a letter to Apple discussing why she won’t be releasing her next album on Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/21/What-I-Read-Last-Week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/21/What-I-Read-Last-Week/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Reads&amp;#58; 6/14</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy and constantly find myself reading articles around the web. I then share the “good ones” with my immediate network. This inspired me to post my finds each week. Feel free to read the ones that intrigue you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/05/18/tomorrows-advance-man?currentPage=all&quot;&gt;Tomorrow’s Advance Man&lt;/a&gt;: Tad Friend writes about the mind of Marc Andreesen, co-founder of a16z (one of Silicon Valley’s top VC firms) and his plan to win the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/how-to-be-a-growth-hacker-an-airbnbcraigslist-case-study/&quot;&gt;Growth Hacker is the new VP Marketing&lt;/a&gt;: Andrew Chen discusses the importance of Growth Hackers. Growth hackers are a hybrid of marketer and coder, one who looks at the traditional question of “How do I get customers for my product?” and answers with A/B tests, landing pages, viral factor, email deliverability, and Open Graph.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.onemonth.com/y-combinator-and-the-one-metric-that-matters&quot;&gt;Y Combinator and The One Metric that Matters&lt;/a&gt;: Mattan Griffel talks about the one metric that matters, growth. Discussing how at YC you learn that growth is the only essential thing you need to be a startup. Everything else follows.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/06/03/uber-an-oral-history/a&quot;&gt;Uber: An oral history&lt;/a&gt;: Five of the company’s earliest employees reflect on how they arrived at Uber, what their tasks were, and managing its sudden growth.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/the-next-feature-fallacy-the-fallacy-that-the-next-new-feature-will-suddenly-make-people-use-your-product/?utm_source=andrewchen&amp;amp;utm_campaign=53a7ad7a0e-RSS_EMAIL_CAMPAIGN&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=0_c1fae7e415-53a7ad7a0e-91069489&quot;&gt;Next Feature Fallacy&lt;/a&gt;: Andrew Chen writes about the fallacy that the next feature you add will suddenly make people want to use the entire product.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 05:31:19 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/14/What-To-Read-This-Week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/06/14/What-To-Read-This-Week/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Reads&amp;#58; 2/28</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy and constantly find myself reading articles around the web. I then share the “good ones” with my immediate network via social platforms. I’ve been inspired to post my finds each week. Feel free to read the ones that intrigue you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.samaltman.com/china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;: Sam Altman discusses how the Chinese economy is overtaking the US economy. The US should try very hard to find a way to grow faster, and to coexist with China.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2011/06/20/foundermarket-fit/&quot;&gt;Founder/Market Fit&lt;/a&gt;: Chris Dixon talks about the need for a founder/market fit. This is when founders have a deep understanding of the market they are entering, and are people who “personify their product, business and ultimately their company.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.geoffralston.com/startup-priorities&quot;&gt;Startup Priorities&lt;/a&gt;: Where should the tiny number of people working on a brand new company spend their time? Geoff Ralston discusses how startups should spend their times and what their priorities should be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/the-most-common-mistake-when-forecasting-growth-for-new-products-and-how-to-fix-it&quot;&gt;The most common mistake when forecasting growth for new products (and how to fix it)&lt;/a&gt;: Andrew Chen talks about how to fix your forecasting by focusing on inputs, not outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.intercom.io/user-onboarding-interview-samuel-hulick/&quot;&gt;Talking User Onboarding With Samuel Hulick&lt;/a&gt;: Samuel Hulick, the CEO of useronboarding.com, discusses the onboarding of a product and the processes that it entails with the cofounder of Intercom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 03:31:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/02/28/What-To-Read-This-Week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/02/28/What-To-Read-This-Week/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My New Years Resolutions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are my new years resolutions (hold me to them). Some of them were mentioned in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2014/12/30/14-Things-I-Learned-in-2014&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read more: My goal is to read 30 books in 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write more: I do not want to put an exact number to this, but I want to continue to contribute to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kevinbastien&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://meetthefounder.co&quot;&gt;Meet the Founder&lt;/a&gt;, and this blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise, sleep, and eat well: My goal is to workout 192 days(around 4 days a week). I need to try and shoot for a regular sleep schedule, and not eat out as much.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue contributing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kbastien&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, and writing code every day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to improve on my time management, and become less of a procrastinator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I’ve actually made a new years resolution, and I plan to stick to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/7xbUcQrTUSJHO/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;charles barkley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 04:31:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/01/01/My-New-Years-Resolutions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2015/01/01/My-New-Years-Resolutions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>14 Things I Learned in 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kevinbastien/14-things-i-learned-in-2014-59134a4d7cd7&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://goo.gl/NKol6r&quot; alt=&quot;scenery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, this year flew by! 2014 has been a great year of growth. I grew as an individual and learned a lot of lessons along the way. I decided to publish this list, even though some of them seem to be pretty cliché. I thought it would be good to reflect back on what exactly it is I learned and the things I will continue to improve on in 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the 14 things I learned in 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn by doing:&lt;/strong&gt; This year I finally figured out what I want to do after college. I really enjoy web development, and knew the only way I would gain the necessary skills to become a web developer would be to work on my own projects. I began attending hackathons, creating things, and learning new languages and frameworks. Although I am not the greatest developer, I feel that I have grown and am more confident than I was at the beginning of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want it, go and get it:&lt;/strong&gt; I have been fortunate to have a lot of helpful mentors. One of the most rewarding things I have learned from them is don’t take no for an answer. This has helped me with meetings, job searches, etc. Don’t hesitate, if you want something, go out there and get it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise, sleep and eat well:&lt;/strong&gt; Living a healthy lifestyle is a major contributor to one’s attitude, energy, and mental state. I was not the healthiest and did not have the best sleeping schedule, but this is one of my resolutions for 2015. Eating whatever I wanted, having late nights and exercising irregularly definitely took a toll on me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue to learn:&lt;/strong&gt; There were multiple times this year where I found myself static— completing the day-to-day school work, but not really trying anything new or challenging. I realized that in order to grow, I need to continue to test myself by trying to learn something new everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure is just another way of learning:&lt;/strong&gt; I have always been very competitive, so I do not take failure lightly. When I fail, I am always hard on myself. This year I taught myself that failure is just another way of learning. Once you fail at something, you learn from that mistake, and do whatever it is better the next time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surround yourself with like minded individuals:&lt;/strong&gt; Jim Rohn once said, “you are the average of the five people you spend the most time with.” I cannot agree more. I started to surround myself with determined individuals that I not only look up to, but that I learn from. This had a huge impact in my growth this year. Another saying that really stuck with me is, “place yourself in a room where everyone is smarter than you.” This will help you learn from everyone around you, and even if it doesn’t seem like it, they will learn from you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; I used to always complain when my parents told me I had to read, and never was one to read school textbooks. I am always reading articles and finally started reading books this year that interest me, from books about startups to fictional novels like The Art of Racing in the Rain (really good book that I just finished, you should check it out!). I believe that this will pay off and help me communicate better and keep me well-informed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet new people:&lt;/strong&gt; I learned that I had to reach out and meet new people, not just at my University, not just in Portland, but from all over. I would sometimes limit myself to who was immediately around me. I learned that I need to go out to local meetups, conferences, and hackathons to meet like minded individuals. I have been fortunate to meet some amazing people and made a lot of new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do things that make you uncomfortable:&lt;/strong&gt; This is something I have to continue to do in 2015. Something that I have yet to overcome is public speaking. I do not know why I get so nervous, but I could do a presentation about myself and my mind would still go blank. If I continue to put myself in uncomfortable situations like public speaking, it will force me to overcome the sense of discomfort, and ultimately forcing me to learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t care about what others think:&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the hardest concepts to overcome. To some degree, everyone cares what certain people think. I used to care what everyone thinks, but have quickly realized this is unproductive and destructive. If you care about what others think, it will only limit you, and you will not reach your full potential. In the end, I have learned to do what makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write more:&lt;/strong&gt; This also happens to be one of my resolutions. I started a blog this year, Meet the Founder, where I interview startup founders. This helped me start writing more, but was still not enough. So in 2015 I am making it my goal to write more. The more I write, the more I will improve. It does not matter to me if anybody reads my work, writing more will allow me to express myself, and I enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer a hand:&lt;/strong&gt; This is something that I need to do more. Volunteering does not have to be something you find as a burden. Volunteer for events that you find interest in. Offer to help others with projects they are working on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything will work out:&lt;/strong&gt; No matter what it is—whether it is grades, money, jobs—it will work out. Keeping a positive outlook and not stressing about the little things has helped me. “Don’t sweat the small stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflect on your day:&lt;/strong&gt; Beginning around early September, I began writing down three things: something good that happened that day, something I was grateful for and what I did that day to help someone out. I would even do this after long stressful days, which happened to be the most helpful. This helped me have a better perspective on how that day actually went, and put me in a better mood.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you had an amazing year, and here’s to a new year for new adventures. Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/6FkXvuwt9MAFi/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;popbottles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 04:31:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2014/12/30/14-Things-I-Learned-in-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.kevinbastien.com/2014/12/30/14-Things-I-Learned-in-2014/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
